Reed Turgeon

Full Stack Software Engineer

turgeon.dev@gmail.com | 508-446-6633

ReedTurgeon.com | linkedin.com/in/reedturgeon | github.com/MrT3313

Since my earliest memories my experiences have been grounded in teamwork. This is evident in, to highlight a few, my family selling the raspberries grown in our yard when I was a toddler, earning my Eagle Scout in high school, or successfully growing and selling a startup after graduating college.

These experiences have revealed to me that in either a leading or supporting role I enjoy putting in the work. In that vein I welcome constructive criticism as it facilitates my main goal to iterate on who I am today in order to become a better person, teammate, and developer tomorrow. Should you decide to have me join your team you can expect a consistent commitment to my work, the team, and your organization.

COMPETENCIES

Agile Development | JavaScript | Python
React | React Hooks | Redux | HTML | CSS | LESS / Sass | Styled Components | MaterialUI
SQL | Postgres | Express | NodeJS | Jest | Supertest | Cypress | Django | Netlify | Heroku | Git

PROJECTS

BookShelf (Project Link | Codebase)

A single page application to find, read, and review books Postgres | Express | React | NodeJS

• Independently designed and built with a focus on well documented, small feature releases

Conway's Game of Life (Project Link | Codebase)

Zero-player cellular automaton

React Hooks

• Independently built to explore simulation logic and practice React state management with Hooks

WORK EXPERIENCE

Lambda School, Computer Science Section Lead – Remote

February 2020 – April 2020

- Responsible for 16 Team Leads that oversaw ~150 students
- Monitored all clerical submissions and facilitated effective communication between each Team Lead and the Student Success Coordinators

Lambda School, Full Stack Web Development Team Lead – Remote

July 2019 – December 2019

- Technical mentor for 7–10 students: Held daily 1:1's and team stand-up meetings via Zoom to address technical challenges, reinforce lecture material and lead JavaScript whiteboard challenges
- Project Lead for 4 Build Weeks: Guided groups of 7-14 developers in delivering one project inclusive of all Lambda's curriculum tracks (Full Stack Web, Android, IOS, Data Science, and UX)

PiraShield, Inc., Startup Comptroller – Wellesley MA.

December 2016 – July 2018

- Finance: Designed and managed all financial recording and reporting systems
- Management: Designed an operational management system to identify, track and communicate performance
- Results: These systems supported the company through $\sim 3000\%$ revenue growth (\$800/Mo \$25,000/Mo) and were integral in the due diligence process and sale of the company to a European competitor

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development

Lambda School, Remote Real-Time Education Model

November 2018 – April 2020

BS: Business Administration, Finance Concentration

Babson College, Wellesley MA

September 2012 – May 2016